travelsearch.com 2005-12-16

# Cheap Airline Tickets, Discount Hotels and Airfare - SideStep Travel

[ ](https://digitalid.verisign.com/as2/e375a16fcb78caee11d0d196e82afdbc) The SideStep is a service owned and operated by SideStep, Inc. ("SideStep") and is comprised of a collection of software and hardware that facilitates your ability to search, compare and purchase travel products and services (such as airline tickets, hotel rooms, and rental cars)(the "Service"). Subject to your agreement to certain terms and conditions in the Software Use Agreement and/or SideStep Terms of Service, you can access and use the Service through: 

>   * software that you download to your web browser (the "SideStep Software"); 
>   * the SideStep web site at www.SideStep.com ("SideStep Web Site") and other SideStep web sites as determined by SideStep from time to time; 
>   * a third party web site with which SideStep has established a relationship; 
>   * a SideStep or third party marketing vehicle (e.g. email); or 
>   * other mechanisms as determined by SideStep from time to time. 
> 

We at SideStep respect your privacy and do not sell, rent, or loan any personally identifiable information regarding our users to any third party except with regards to information required to book the travel you select on partner sites. We hold any information you provide with the utmost care and security, and will not use it in ways to which you have not consented. 

We are committed to you to make your on-line experience satisfying and safe. If you have registered with SideStep, we will notify you via email of any material change in the use of your personally identifiable information and give you the opportunity to opt-out before that new use goes into effect. We will also prominently post such changes on The SideStep Web Site at least 30-days prior to their going into effect. We encourage you to review our Privacy Policy whenever you visit the SideStep Web Site or access and use the Service. 

The purpose of this Privacy Policy is to inform you of the following: 

  * What kind of information does SideStep collect about you?
  * How will the information that SideStep collects be used?
  * With whom does SideStep share the information it collects about you?
  * What are the opt-out choices SideStep provides you regarding the collection, use, and distribution of your information?
  * What security procedures does SideStep use to protect against the loss, misuse, or alteration of information collected by the company?
  * How can I access the information SideStep has about me or correct it?

_Name and email address_  
When you download the Software, you have the option (but are not required) to provide SideStep with your name and email address. If you provide us with your email address we may use it to send you information about the Service, new features and upgrades to the Service and new services offered by SideStep. You also have the option to give us permission to use your email address to send you information on special promotions and offers. If you have downloaded the Software, you may opt-out of receiving these types of mailings by un-checking the box in the personalization section in your SideStep (click on the "My Preferences" link). If you have not downloaded the Software but have opted to receive other emails from SideStep (e.g. email newsletters), you can click the unsubscribe link on one of the emails you receive in order to unsubscribe. 

_IP Addresses and Computer Information_   
If you access and use the Service, our Web server logs typical information, including: 

>   * The URL of the page requested 
>   * The time and date of the request 
>   * The type, version, and configuration of Web browser being used 
>   * The type of Operating System being used 
>   * The URL of the site where you clicked on a link to get to the SideStep Web site. This URL might contain a code to help identify the specific advertisement clicked on. 
>   * The IP address to which a copy of the page you requested is to be sent for display by your browser 
> 

This information is completely anonymous. This information helps us determine if your computer has the minimum requirements necessary to download the Software and is used to help us improve the Service. 

SideStep uses cookies in several ways. We use cookies to track your usage of the Service to assist us in serving advertisements through our advertising networks. "Cookies" are small text files that are stored by your browser on your computer's hard drive. 

_Transaction Information_   
SideStep collects transaction information such as services purchased, sites used and offers accepted by our users. In the event that you make a purchase with a travel provider through the Service, we collect the information that you provide to the travel supply including itinerary information such as name, dates of travel, travel origination and destination, and payment information. As a general rule, we do not collect credit card numbers. The only exception is if you purchase travel services from a travel provider for which we host the booking process. In the limited cases where we host the booking process, we electronically package the booking information that you provide to us (including your credit card number in encrypted form) and transmit the information to the travel provider. Other than this one transmission, Sidestep does not use your credit card number and does not retain or share your card number with anyone other than the travel provider from whom you are making your purchase. 

We gather this information in order to facilitate transactions on your behalf, to personalize and improve our service offerings to you and to ensure that we are compensated by our partners. In order to facilitate your purchase, we have to disclose your information to the travel providers that you have selected. We also use this information in the aggregate to better understand what purchases users want to make and help provide better offers and a more effective service. We may offer personalized services for those people who choose to use them. We may also develop aggregate - but not individual - reports for our partners. An example of a summary report might be "500 users booked travel to a specific city during the month of November." As mentioned above, if you provide us with your email address, we may use it to send you information we think is useful, including information about special offers, new products and services. It is our policy to not send email messages to users who do not wish to receive them. You always have the opportunity to opt-out of receiving such emails in the manner described in paragraph 1 above and paragraph 4 below. 

Your personal information is never sold, rented or given to a third party other than the travel providers with which you decide to book your travel. Trend and aggregate data about users' habits and use of the Service is tracked by SideStep to enable SideStep to provide its users with an increasingly improved Service. Beyond these disclosures, we do not share your personal information with any third party without your consent, except (i) when we believe it is required by law or judicial authority; (ii) to safeguard SideStep's rights or property; or (iii) if SideStep should ever file for bankruptcy or merge with another company, or if SideStep should decide to buy, sell or reorganize some part or all of its business, SideStep may be required to disclose your personal information to prospective or actual purchasers or receive personal information from sellers. It is SideStep's practice to seek appropriate protection for information disclosed or received in these types of transactions. 

If you choose to share personally identifiable information with SideStep, you can control whether we contact you. You may change your mind at any time. If you submitted personal information in connection with your use of the Software, you can always change your account information by clicking the "My Preferences" link. If there is ever a change to how SideStep uses personally identifiable information, we will post that change to our online Privacy Policy and notify you via email, providing you the opportunity to opt-out. 

If you have downloaded the Software, at any time, you may review and update your personally identifiable information by clicking on the "My Preferences" link from within the Software. From this window, SideStep gives users of the following options: 

>   * Users may un-check specific boxes in the "SideStep Preferences" section to opt-out of receiving SideStep emails, and 
>   * Users of the Software may uninstall the Software at any time to stop using the Service via the Software by selecting "Add/Remove Programs" from the Control Panel. In the dialog box that opens, select SideStep from the menu of applications. After clicking on "SideStep," click on the button that says "Remove." 
> 

If you have not downloaded the Software but have opted to receive emails from SideStep (e.g. email newsletters), you can click the unsubscribe link on one of the emails you receive in order to unsubscribe. 

Regardless of email contact opt-in status, SideStep reserves the right to send a one-time registration confirmation email and infrequent alert messages to our users to inform you of specific changes that may impact your ability to use the Service. 

SideStep operates secure data networks protected by industry standard firewall and password protection systems. Our internal security and privacy policies are periodically reviewed and enhanced as necessary and only authorized individuals have access to the information provided by our users. 

While SideStep takes reasonable steps to secure your personal information, no system is fault proof. If SideStep's security systems are breached SideStep may attempt to notify you electronically and, by using the Service and/or providing personal information to us, you agree that we can notify you electronically. SideStep may post a notice on the SideStep Web Site if a security breach occurs. If this happens, you will need a web browser enabling you to view the SideStep Web Site. SideStep may also send an email to you at the email address you have provided to us. Depending on where you live, you may have a legal right to receive notice of a security breach in writing. To receive free written notice of a security breach (or to withdraw your consent from receiving electronic notice) you should notify us at privacy@Sidestep.com. If your email address changes and you have provided SideStep with personal information, you should notify SideStep at [privacy@Sidestep.com](mailto:privacy@Sidestep.com) so that we can communicate with you if necessary. 

Children under 13 should not send any information about themselves to SideStep. If a child under 13 submits information through any part of the Service, and we learn the person submitting the information is a child, we will attempt to delete this information as soon as possible. Because we do not knowingly collect any personal information from children under 13, we do not use or disclose such information to third parties. 

SideStep has appointed a privacy officer responsible for assisting you with privacy-related issues. If you would like to change or update your personal information or preferences, please follow the instructions described in paragraph 4 above. We are committed to providing you with reasonable access to the information we have about you and reasonably assisting you in managing the personal information you share with us. 

If you have any questions, comments, or concerns about this Privacy Policy or personal information you have provided to us, please email us at [privacy@Sidestep.com](mailto:privacy@Sidestep.com) or contact us by mail at: 

SideStep, Inc.  
3131 Jay Street, Ste 210  
Santa Clara, CA 95054  
Attention: Privacy Officer 

09/15/04
